♪Menelan kegelisahan♪
♪메넬란 케겔리사한♪
♪Your roots firmly grip this land♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 이 땅을 굳건히 붙잡고 있습니다♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪멘게자르 옴박♪
♪My leaves cross a distant border♪
♪나의 나뭇잎은 먼 국경을 넘어간다♪
♪Kejauhan Menants♪
♪케자우한 메난츠♪
♪Eternity is the ultimate goal♪
♪영원함이 궁극적인 목표입니다♪
♪Separating again after meeting♪
♪만남 후 또 헤어짐♪
♪Back apart after leaning in♪
♪기대고 뒤로 물러나기♪
♪I never forget♪
♪절대 잊지 않아요♪
♪A sword flash splits the colored sky♪
♪ 색빛 하늘을 가르는 검의 섬광 ♪
♪Abandoned dreams shattered♪
♪버려진 꿈은 산산이 부서졌다♪
♪Breaking through fearlessly♪
♪용맹스럽게 돌파♪
♪Looking at the waves of the anchored sails, the world has changed♪
♪정박된 돛의 파도를 보니 세상이 달라졌다♪
♪Armor and makeup scattered in the air♪
♪갑옷과 화장이 공중에 흩뿌려집니다♪
♪Ever scared, the blood doesn't dry up, and dreaming of twilight♪
♪무서워도 피가 마르지 않고 황혼을 꿈꾸며♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요♪
♪Youth is not wasted♪
♪청춘은 낭비되지 않는다♪
♪Stand firm, unite with each other, and raise your sword with you♪
♪ 굳건히 서서 서로 뭉쳐 함께 검을 들어라 ♪
♪Seeing sparks fall on our shoulders♪
♪ 우리 어깨에 불꽃이 떨어지는 걸 보니♪
♪There are no regrets in this mortal world♪
♪이 세상엔 후회란 없어♪
=Love Trip=
=사랑여행=
=Episode 19=
=제19화=
Don't worry, Dad.
걱정하지 마세요, 아빠.
Ananda has prepared a fast horse.
아난다는 빠른 말을 준비했습니다.
If the war situation is unfavorable,
전쟁 상황이 불리할 경우,
Ananda will definitely accompany your father's retreat to the south.
아난다는 반드시 당신 아버지의 남쪽 퇴각에 동행할 것입니다.
As long as entering the banks of the Jiangnan River, with the natural dangers there,
자연의 위험이 도사리고 있는 강남강(Jiangnan River) 기슭에 들어서기만 하면 ,
we will definitely be fine.
우리는 분명 괜찮을 거예요.
Father, if the war situation is unfavorable,
아버지, 전황이 불리 하면
Ananda is willing to stay here
아난다는 여기에 머물 의향이 있습니다
lead the rearguard to block the enemy's forces.
후위대를 이끌고 적군을 막아낸다.
At that time, please go first with your father.
그 때에는 먼저 아버지와 함께 가십시오.
Second Sister,
둘째 자매,
Your loyalty and courage are truly commendable.
당신의 충성심과 용기는 정말 칭찬할 만합니다.
Brother is the eldest son.
형은 큰 아들입니다.
In the future, this country and your father will have to rely on Big Brother.
앞으로 이 나라도, 너희 아버지도 빅브라더에게 의지해야 할 것이다.
If I could stay here to intercept the enemy forces
만약 내가 여기에 남아서 적군을 요격할 수 있다면
and protect the safety of your Father and Sister,
그리고 네 아버지와 자매의 안전을 지켜라 .
even if I die, that is also worth it.
내가 죽어도 그만한 가치가 있습니다.
Lai'er is really a good, filial child.
라이어는 정말 착하고 효도하는 아이예요.
Second Sister.
둘째 자매.
Second Sister, you can't...
둘째 누나, 그러면 안 돼요...
His Majesty!
폐하!
Report, Your Majesty!
보고하세요, 폐하!
There's news from the front lines!
최전선에서 소식이 왔습니다!
Say it quickly!
빨리 말해!
King Qin has captured West Changjing.
진왕이 서장경을 점령하였다.
Congratulations, His Majesty.
축하드립니다, 폐하.
King Qin defeats Sun Jing
진왕이 손경을 물리치고
and had charged into West Changjing with his troops.
그의 군대와 함께 서부 창징 으로 돌격했습니다 .
What?
무엇?
- Congratulations, Father!
- 축하해요, 아버지!
Your father is protected and blessed by Heaven
너희 아버지는 하늘의 보호와 축복을 받으셨느니라
so that the new King of Qin could retake West Changjing!
새로운 진왕이 서장경을 탈환할 수 있도록!
Congratulations, Dad!
축하해요, 아빠!
His father placed King Qin in an important position
그의 아버지는 진왕을 요직에 두었다
so that the new King of Qin could retake West Changjing!
새로운 진왕이 서장경을 탈환할 수 있도록!
Your father looks far ahead
네 아버지는 훨씬 앞을 내다보시네
and this is a blessing for this country!
그리고 이것은 이 나라에 대한 축복입니다!
Good! Very good!
좋은! 매우 좋은!
Counselor Wu's words were true.
우 상담사의 말이 사실이었습니다.
I am destined to be emperor.
나는 황제가 될 운명이다.
As long as I ascend the throne as emperor,
내가 황제로서 왕위에 오르는 한,
all the people in this country will be saved.
이 나라의 모든 사람들이 구원을 받을 것이다.
- Congratulations, Father! - Congratulations, Your Majesty!
- 축하해요, 아버지! - 축하드립니다, 폐하!
(Istana Chaoqian)
(이스타나 차오첸)
That year, when he was 16 years old,
그 해, 그가 16세가 되던 해,
according to tradition, I must enter the palace
전통에 따르면 나는 궁전에 들어가야 한다
to bid farewell to the Former Emperor
전 황제에게 작별 인사를 하기 위해
before leaving for Laolan Border.
라오란 국경으로 떠나기 전.
At that time, I made a mistake.
그 당시 나는 실수를 저질렀습니다.
The Former Emperor was furious
전 황제는 분노했다.
and not willing to meet me.
그리고 나를 만날 생각이 없습니다.
He sent someone to convey a message to me
그는 나에게 메시지를 전하기 위해 사람을 보냈습니다
so that I am satisfied with my fate, do my duty,
내 운명에 만족하고 의무를 다하고
and stop tarnishing the reputation of the descendants of the Li Family.
리씨 가문의 후손 들의 명예를 더럽히는 일을 멈추십시오 .
His Majesty has now reclaimed West Changjing.
폐하께서는 이제 서창징을 되찾으셨습니다.
This will comfort the soul of the Past Emperor in heaven.
이것이 천상황제의 영혼을 위로할 것입니다.
What about the person chasing Sun Jing?
Sun Jing을 쫓는 사람은 어떻습니까 ?
After several times of close combat,
몇 차례 의 접전 끝에,
we still can't hold them.
우리는 아직도 그들을 붙잡을 수 없습니다.
Sun Jing's trusted deputy general protected him tooth and nail.
Sun Jing이 신뢰하는 부장군은 그를 철저하게 보호했습니다.
Sun Jing should still be unconscious now.
Sun Jing은 지금도 의식이 없을 것입니다.
They fought while retreating
그들은 후퇴하면서 싸웠다
and had also retreated all the way to the Tong Border that night.
그리고 그날 밤 통 국경 까지 후퇴하기도 했습니다 .
What about Great General Cui?
최장군은 어떻습니까?
After capturing the city,
도시를 점령한 뒤,
Great General Cui led troops into the palace,
최대장군(崔大將官)이 군대를 이끌고 궁궐로 들어왔다.
then got off the horse in front of Jianyuan Hall
그런 다음 Jianyuan Hall 앞에서 말에서 내 렸습니다.
and entered Yunxiao Terrace from the back.
뒤쪽에서 Yunxiao Terrace로 들어갔습니다 .
He said one sentence, "My enthusiasm has faded, that's all",
그는 "열정이 식었다. 그게 다다"라고 한 마디 했다 .
then led the troops out of the palace
그 후 군대를 이끌고 궁전 밖으로 나갔다.
and headed for the Cui Family Army headquarters outside the city.
그리고 도시 외곽의 추이 가문 군대 본부로 향했습니다 .
"Just that".
"그냥".
I also want to be the same as him, after capturing the city and killing the enemy,
나도 그와 같이 되고 싶다. 도시를 점령하고 적을 죽인 후,
then finally said "that's it" and left.
그러다가 마침내 "그게 다야"라고 말하고 떠났습니다.
That was the style of a true general.
그것이 진정한 장군의 스타일이었다 .
Honourable,
존경합니다,
You and him are not the same.
당신과 그 사람은 같지 않습니다.
However, I am currently very jealous of him.
그러나 나는 현재 그를 매우 질투합니다.
His Majesty came out of Laolan Border,
폐하께서는 라오란 국경에서 나오셨습니다.
leads an army to rescue the emperor and quell the rebellion.
황제를 구출하고 반란을 진압하기 위해 군대를 이끈다 .
Now, you have reclaimed West Changjing.
이제 당신은 서창징을 되찾았습니다.
So, from now on, you are different from everyone.
그러니 이제부터 당신은 모든 사람과 다릅니다.
You also can no longer say you are jealous of other people.
또한 더 이상 다른 사람을 질투한다고 말할 수도 없습니다 .
That's right, it's really boring.
그렇죠, 정말 지루해요.
Di mana Ying?
디 마나 잉?
Was he out of town with Great General Cui?
그는 추이 장군과 함께 외출 중이었나요 ?
It turns out this is the royal palace.
이것이 왕궁이라는 것이 밝혀졌습니다.
Commander,
사령관,
here besides the building is a little taller
여기 건물이 조금 더 높은 것 외에는
and the house is a little bigger, nothing seems different.
그리고 집이 조금 더 커져서 달라진 게 하나도 없는 것 같아요.
Look at it.
보세요.
Where we live now
지금 우리가 사는 곳
named Yuhui Pavilion.
Yuhui Pavilion으로 명명되었습니다.
Ahead is the Jianyuan Hall,
앞에는 Jianyuan Hall이 있습니다.
Aula Qianzheng,
Aula Qianzheng,
dan Aula Jingde.
그리고 Aula Jingde.
These were all the places of the emperors of previous dynasties
이곳은 모두 이전 왕조의 황제가 살았던 곳이었습니다.
take care of governance.
거버넌스에 신경쓰세요.
Behind the high wall is the Palace of the Crown Prince,
높은 성벽 뒤에는 왕세자의 궁전이 있고,
which borders this Yuhui Pavilion.
이 Yuhui Pavilion 과 접해 있습니다 .
Further back is the harem palace.
더 뒤쪽 에는 하렘 궁전이 있습니다.
How many people can live in such a big house?
이렇게 큰 집에 몇 명이 살 수 있나요 ?
The emperor had dozens of sons and hundreds of grandchildren.
황제에게는 수십 명의 아들 과 수백 명의 손자가 있었습니다.
There are many descendants.
후손이 많습니다.
If the palace does not fit, the respective kings will be given
궁전이 맞지 않으면 각각의 왕이 주어질 것입니다
residence outside the palace to live in after marriage.
결혼 후 거주할 궁궐 밖의 거주지 .
Sadly,
슬프게도,
Sun Jing rebelled
쑨징이 반항했다
and wiped out almost all of the descendants of the Li Family.
Li 가문의 거의 모든 후손을 몰살했습니다 .
King Qin came.
진왕이 왔다.
Ying,
잉,
I want to ask for your help on one thing.
한 가지 도움을 요청하고 싶습니다 .
Which matter?
어떤 문제인가요?
The Previous Crown Princess, Madam Xiao,
전 왕세자비 샤오부인,
has endured humiliation and carried heavy burdens.
굴욕을 견디고 무거운 짐을 지셨습니다.
For the sake of poisoning Sun Jing, he himself was also poisoned
Sun Jing을 중독시키기 위해 그 자신도 중독되었습니다.
and now his life is in danger.
이제 그의 생명이 위험에 처해 있습니다.
I want to ask Taozi to treat him.
나는 Taozi에게 그를 치료해달라고 부탁하고 싶습니다.
Because I'm not free,
나는 자유롭지 않기 때문에,
please replace me to take care of him.
저 대신에 그 사람을 돌봐주세요 .
It turns out he was the one who poisoned Sun Jing.
알고 보니 그가 Sun Jing을 독살한 사람이었습니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
For someone who upholds justice so much,
그렇게 정의를 수호하는 사람에게
I will definitely not disappoint you.
나는 결코 당신을 실망시키지 않을 것입니다.
This lip color box is the poison.
이 립 컬러 박스가 독이군요.
Madam said,
부인이 말했다.
if he poisons food,
만약 그가 음식에 독을 넣었다면,
afraid that Sun Jing would notice.
Sun Jing이 알아차릴까봐 두려웠습니다.
So, he put poison in the lip color.
그래서 립 컬러에 독을 넣었어요.
Madam also said that this poison has a sweet aroma
부인도 이 독은 달콤한 향이 난다고 하더군요
and only the floral scent of the lip color can mask the scent.
립 컬러의 꽃향만이 향을 가릴 수 있습니다.
Besides, there is only one chance.
게다가 기회는 단 한 번뿐이다.
On the day the city was attacked,
도시가 공격받던 날,
he immediately smeared the poison on his own lips
그는 즉시 자신의 입술에 독을 발랐습니다.
without caring at all, this poison will also attack his heart.
전혀 신경 쓰지 않으면 이 독도 그의 심장을 공격할 것이다.
Mrs
부인
was determined to die with him.
그와 함께 죽기로 결심했습니다.
(Luoyang)
(뤄양)
- Greetings to your father.
- 아버지께 인사드립니다.
No need to be formal.
형식적일 필요는 없습니다.
- Thank you, Father.
- 고마워요, 신부님.
The King of Qin sent an army outside the city to welcome.
진왕은 성 밖으로 군대를 보내 환영하였다.
As emperor,
황제로서,
I must appear grand when I return to West Changjing
서창징으로 돌아가면 나는 위대해 보일 것이다.
to receive congratulations from the officials.
관계자들로부터 축하를 받기 위해 .
Father, there are several things
아버지, 여러 가지 일이 있어요
which I don't know if I should say it or not.
말해야 할지 말아야 할지 모르겠습니다 .
You don't need to hesitate. Say.
주저할 필요가 없습니다. 말하다.
Now King Qin has reclaimed West Changjing
이제 진왕이 서장경을 되찾았 느니라
and make unmatched contributions.
그리고 비교할 수 없는 기여를 하세요.
How will your father reward the King of Qin?
당신 의 아버지는 진왕에게 어떻게 상을 주실 것입니까?
This...
이것...
He is my son.
그는 내 아들이다.
After all, isn't sharing his father's burden
결국, 아버지의 짐을 공유 하지 않는 것입니다.
is it an obligation?
의무인가요?
Why should you be rewarded?
왜 보상을 받아야 합니까?
Your father has crowned the Third Brother as the King of Qin.
당신의 아버지는 셋째 형을 진왕으로 삼았습니다 .
Among the kings, only the title of King of Qin is the highest.
왕 중에서 는 진왕(秦王)의 칭호만이 가장 높다.
If rewarded again,
또 보상을 받으면
he could only be crowned Crown Prince.
그는 오직 왕세자로만 왕위에 오를 수 있었다.
You said you appointed him Crown Prince?
그를 왕세자로 임명했다고 했죠 ?
By direct line of descent, he has no rights.
직계존속상 그에게는 권리가 없습니다.
Tell me, why should he be appointed Crown Prince?
말해 보세요, 왜 그가 왕세자로 임명되어야 합니까?
If at this time your father
만약 이 시간에 네 아버지가
did not intend to appoint the Third Brother as Crown Prince
셋째 형을 왕세자로 임명할 생각은 없었다.
while he is not rewarded
그 사람은 보상을 받지 못하는 동안
even though he has made a great contribution,
비록 그가 큰 공헌을 했지만,
afraid that there would be people with ulterior motives
다른 동기를 가진 사람들이 있을까봐 두렵다.
which incites the three forces to rebel
세 세력의 반란을 불러일으킨다.
and the situation will be serious.
상황은 심각할 것이다.
This is... rebellion?
이건... 반란인가요?
This...
이것...
Don't panic, Dad.
당황하지 마세요, 아빠.
After returning to the palace,
궁궐로 돌아온 후,
Your father can open the palace treasury.
당신의 아버지는 궁전 금고를 열 수 있습니다 .
It is said that Sun Jing left in a hurry
쑨징이 급히 떠났다고 한다
and do not bring valuables that are in the palace treasury.
그리고 궁궐 창고에 있는 귀중품도 가져오지 마십시오 .
Treasury?
국고?
Right, your father.
그렇죠, 당신 아버지.
What if your father opened the palace treasury
네 아버지가 궁궐 금고를 열었다면 ?
and provide rewards
보상을 제공하고
to the soldiers who reclaimed West Changjing?
서창징을 수복한 군인들에게 ?
The soldiers will surely be grateful for His Majesty's gift.
군인들은 폐하의 선물에 대해 분명히 감사할 것입니다.
Even if someone incites, they will not join in making trouble.
누군가 선동하여도 문제를 일으키는 데 가담하지 않을 것입니다.
Jun'er and Lai'er's methods are indeed good.
Jun'er와 Lai'er의 방법은 정말 좋습니다.
Once I return to West Changjing, I will open the palace treasury
내가 서장경으로 돌아가면 궁궐의 보물창고를 열겠노라
and give rewards to all three teams.
그리고 세 팀 모두에게 보상을 주세요.
His Majesty's goodness is great, beneficial for the country forever.
폐하의 선하심은 위대하여 영원히 나라에 이롭습니다.
Long live forever!
영원히 살아라!
(Chaoqian Palace) His Majesty's virtue is great,
(조천궁) 폐하의 덕이 크시도다
beneficial to the country forever.
영원히 나라에 유익이 됩니다.
Long live forever!
영원히 살아라!
Mrs.
부인.
Madam, are you awake?
부인, 일어났어요?
Madam, you are awake.
부인, 일어나셨군요.
It's good to be aware.
알아두시면 좋습니다.
That means the effects of the poison have subsided.
이는 독의 효과가 사라졌음을 의미합니다.
Long live His Majesty!
폐하 만세!
Outside...
밖의...
What's that sound outside?
밖에서 들리는 소리는 무엇입니까?
Mrs,
부인,
You've been unconscious for days.
당신은 며칠 동안 의식을 잃었습니다 .
By leading the Western Border Army,
서부국경군을 지휘하여 ,
His Majesty the King of Qin has reclaimed West Changjing,
진왕 폐하께서 서장 경(西長景)을 되찾으셨으니
then welcomed His Majesty back to the palace.
그런 다음 폐하께서 궁전으로 돌아오신 것을 환영했습니다.
Today,
오늘,
He received congratulations from the officials.
관계자들로부터 축하를 받았습니다 .
That voice outside
밖에서 들려오는 그 목소리
was the grateful voice of the third team.
세 번째 팀의 고마운 목소리 였다 .
We... we won.
우리가... 우리가 이겼어요.
Be careful, madam.
조심하세요, 부인.
We won.
우리가 이겼어요.
Don't worry, madam.
걱정하지 마세요, 부인.
Who are these two ladies?
이 두 여자는 누구입니까?
Madam, this is Commander He of the Cui Family Army.
부인, 저는 추이 가문 군대의 허 사령관입니다 .
He was asked by King Qin to come and treat his Lady.
그는 진왕으로부터 와서 그의 부인을 치료해 달라는 요청을 받았습니다.
Thanks to Miss Taozi brought by Commander He,
허 사령관이 데려온 미스 타오자 덕분에
who dispenses medicine carefully every day,
매일 정성스럽게 약을 조제하는 사람 ,
The poison in Madam finally disappeared.
마님의 독이 마침내 사라졌습니다.
Thank you, Commander He.
감사합니다, He 사령관님.
Madam upholds justice
부인은 정의를 수호합니다
and save everyone in this country.
그리고 이 나라의 모든 사람을 구해주세요.
I should be the one thanking Madam
나는 부인에게 감사 해야 해요
represents everyone in this country.
이 나라의 모든 사람을 대표합니다.
I don't deserve Madam's thanks.
나는 부인의 감사를 받을 자격이 없습니다 .
This palace is not bad.
이 궁전은 나쁘지 않습니다.
It's just that these curtains are a bit worn.
단지 이 커튼이 조금 낡았을 뿐입니다.
Replace everything with new ones.
모든 것을 새 것으로 교체하십시오.
Good.
좋은.
Greetings to your father.
아버지께 인사드립니다.
No need to be formal.
형식적일 필요는 없습니다.
King Qin, what a coincidence you came.
진왕님, 정말 우연이군요.
This time, you made a huge contribution in reclaiming West Changjing.
이번에 당신은 서창징을 되찾는 데 큰 공헌을 했습니다.
Say, what gift do you want?
말해봐, 무슨 선물을 원하니?
Gold and silver or fiefdoms?
금과 은 또는 영지?
His Majesty,
폐하,
Ananda did not want any gifts.
아난다는 어떤 선물도 원하지 않았습니다 .
Ananda wants to ask for orders.
아난다는 명령을 요청하고 싶어합니다.
After Ananda sent people to find the Emperor's First Grandson,
아난다가 황제의 첫째 손자를 찾기 위해 사람들을 보낸 후 ,
please His Majesty agree to welcome back the Emperor's First Grandson.
폐하께서는 천황의 첫째 손자를 환영하는 데 동의해 주시기 바랍니다.
The Emperor's First Grandson?
황제의 첫째 손자?
When Sun Jing rebelled,
손징이 반란을 일으켰을 때,
he killed the First Emperor and the First Crown Prince.
그는 시황제 와 태자를 죽였습니다.
Fortunately Han Chang, General Yunchang,
다행히 한창, 윈창장군,
protect the Emperor's First Grandson to escape.
황제의 첫째 손자를 보호하여 탈출하세요.
His Majesty,
폐하,
The Emperor's First Grandson
황제의 첫째 손자
is a direct descendant of the First Emperor.
제1대 황제의 직계 후손이다 .
Please His Majesty agree to welcome back the Emperor's First Grandson
폐하께서는 천황의 첫째 손자를 환영하는 데 동의해 주시기 바랍니다.
and set him as the crown prince.
그리고 그를 왕세자로 세웠습니다.
This is a big problem, I have to consider it first.
이것은 큰 문제이므로 먼저 고려해야합니다.
His Majesty, the First Emperor passed away
제1대 황제 폐하께서 돌아가셨습니다.
and the Former Crown Prince sacrificed for the country.
그리고 나라를 위해 희생한 전 왕세자 .
The Emperor's First Grandson inheriting the throne was a matter of course.
황제의 첫째 손자가 왕위를 물려받는 것은 당연했다.
I told you I would consider it first.
내가 먼저 고려해 보겠다고 말했잖아.
Go home first.
먼저 집에 가세요.
You've been quite busy lately.
요즘 꽤 바쁘셨군요.
Go home and rest.
집에 가서 쉬세요.
If there is no need, do not enter the palace first.
필요가 없다면 먼저 궁전에 들어가지 마십시오.
Good.
좋은.
Mrs,
부인,
eat again
다시 먹어
Bibi Jin,
Bibi Jin,
is Sun Jing still alive?
Sun Jing 아직 살아있나요?
Mrs.
부인.
Correct.
옳은.
Logically,
논리적으로,
I should be worried
걱정해야지
because of this big threat
이 큰 위협 때문에
still not removed.
아직 제거되지 않았습니다.
However, when I remember
그런데 제 기억으로는
how he rushed to the palace covered in blood
그가 어떻게 피투성이가 되어 궁전으로 달려갔는지
and hold my hand...
그리고 내 손을 잡아...
What was I thinking at that time?
그 때 나는 무슨 생각을 하고 있었나?
I am the First Crown Princess.
나는 첫 번째 왕세자비입니다.
Mrs.
부인.
During the days I spent in the Crown Prince's Palace,
내가 왕궁에서 보낸 날들 동안 ,
I'm alive,
나는 살아있다
but like an empty shell.
그러나 빈 껍질과 같습니다.
Only when I'm with him,
그 사람과 함께 있을 때만,
I feel like I really am a human being.
내가 정말 인간이 된 것 같은 느낌이 든다.
However, I am the First Crown Princess.
그러나 나는 첫 번째 왕세자비이다.
I'm not supposed to like it.
나는 그것을 좋아하지 않아야합니다.
Mrs.
부인.
I know.
알아요.
I won't discuss it any more.
더 이상 논의하지 않겠습니다.
No one will ever know
아무도 모를 거야
the past between me and him,
나와 그 사람 사이의 과거,
Nor will anyone else know who I am now
나도 지금 내가 누구인지 다른 사람은 알 수 없을 거예요
still love her.
아직도 그녀를 사랑해요.
Mrs.
부인.
My relationship with Sun Jing
Sun Jing과의 관계
insincere and full of hypocrisy.
성실하지 못하고 위선이 가득합니다.
I've lost my reputation.
나는 평판을 잃었습니다.
It wouldn't be a pity if I died.
죽어도 안타깝지 않을 것 같아요.
Mrs,
부인,
You can't say that.
그렇게 말할 수는 없습니다.
Stay cool,
침착,
I won't die now.
나는 이제 죽지 않을 것이다.
I still have to confirm that the Emperor's First Grandson
아직 천황의 첫째 손자가 맞는지 확인을 해야 하는데
come back safely.
무사히 돌아오세요.
I want to see it
난 그걸 보길 원해
grow up well.
잘 자라라.
At the time,
당시,
I'll just be able to go to the afterlife
그냥 사후세계로 갈 수 있을 것 같아
to meet the Former Crown Prince.
전 왕세자를 만나기 위해.
Mrs.
부인.
Don't.
하지 않다.
(Residence of the King of Qin)
(진왕의 거주지)
(Legenda Jiang Ziya)
(레전다 장쯔야)
Are you still willing to come visit me?
아직도 나를 방문할 의향이 있습니까?
I thought Big Miss Cui had forgotten about me a long time ago.
나는 추이 양이 나를 오래 전에 잊어버린 줄 알았다.
Why is His Highness the King of Qin so forgetful?
진왕 전하께서는 왜 그렇게 잊어버리십니까?
It was clearly His Majesty King Qin who asked me to take care of Madam Xiao.
나에게 소부인을 돌보라고 한 사람은 분명히 진왕 폐하였습니다 .
Mrs. Xiao's health has improved a lot today.
오늘 샤오 부인의 건강이 많이 좋아졌습니다.
He could already talk after eating a bowl of porridge.
그는 죽 한 그릇을 먹고 나면 벌써 말을 할 수 있게 되었다 .
So, I just had time to leave the palace and visit you.
그래서 나는 방금 궁궐을 떠나 당신을 방문할 시간이 있었습니다.
I went straight to you without having time to visit my father,
아버지를 만나러 갈 시간도 없이 곧장 당신에게 갔더니
but you don't appreciate it. If that's the case, I'll just go.
하지만 당신은 그것을 감사하지 않습니다. 그렇다면 그냥 가겠습니다.
I want to go out of town to meet my father.
나는 아버지를 만나러 시내로 나가고 싶다 .
(Broad and Open Minded) I'm just kidding.
(넓고 열린 마음) 농담이에요.
That's all, accompany me for a moment.
그게 다야, 잠시만 동행해줘.
Later I will go out of town with you
나중에 나는 너와 함께 마을 밖으로 나갈 것이다
to visit Great General Cui. How?
추이 장군을 만나러 갑니다 . 어떻게?
You're not afraid that my father will tie you up again
우리 아버지가 널 또 묶을 까봐 두렵지 않구나
and put you in a box?
그리고 당신을 상자에 넣어?
You will definitely save me.
당신은 반드시 나를 구해줄 것입니다.
That's not necessarily true.
반드시 그런 것은 아닙니다.
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
Is there anything that makes you unhappy?
당신을 불행하게 만드는 것이 있나요 ?
Otherwise, why are you lying here alone?
그렇지 않으면 왜 여기 혼자 누워 있는 걸까요
No, I read books because I'm bored,
아니요, 심심해서 책을 읽습니다.
then almost fell asleep because he was so bored.
그러다가 너무 지루해서 거의 잠들 뻔했어요 .
I heard His Majesty opening the palace treasury
나는 폐하께서 궁궐 금고를 여는 소리를 들었습니다.
and use its contents to reward all three teams.
콘텐츠를 사용하여 세 팀 모두에게 보상을 제공합니다.
Logically speaking, you have made a great contribution,
논리적으로 말하면 당신은 큰 공헌을 했습니다.
So the King of Qin's Residence should have many guests.
그러므로 진왕의 집에는 손님이 많아야 합니다.
Why so quiet and lonely?
왜 그렇게 조용하고 외로운 걸까요?
I don't like those civil officials.
나는 그 공무원들을 좋아하지 않는다.
After all, I am the King of Qin who leads the Western Border Army.
결국 나는 서부 국경군을 이끄는 진왕이다 .
I am not free to make friends with civil officials.
나는 공무원들과 친구가 될 자유가 없습니다.
If I were friends with the general,
내가 장군과 친구였다면,
it will arouse suspicion and be easily misunderstood.
그것은 의심을 불러일으키고 쉽게 오해될 것입니다.
So, I thought
그래서 나는 생각했다.
to refuse guests.
손님을 거절하는 것.
Civil and military officials also know my nature
민군 관계자들 도 내 성격을 알아요
so did not dare to come.
그래서 감히 오지 못했어요.
It's okay if it's someone else.
다른 사람이어도 괜찮습니다.
However, shouldn't you visit Prime Minister Gu?
그런데 구 총리를 찾아가면 안 되는 걸까요?
During the day at the palace meeting, the position of Prime Minister Gu was restored.
낮에는 궁궐회의에서 구 총리의 지위가 회복됐다.
His Majesty wanted to give him the title,
폐하께서는 그에게 칭호를 주시고자 하셨습니다.
but Prime Minister Gu knelt down to thank him and refused.
그러나 구 총리는 무릎을 꿇고 감사 인사를 전하며 거절했다.
He is amazing.
그는 놀랍습니다.
He also helped a lot in reclaiming West Changjing.
그는 또한 서창징을 되찾는 일에도 많은 도움을 주었습니다 .
So, after the palace meeting that day,
그래서 그날 궁궐회의가 끝난 후,
I went to Prime Minister Gu's Residence and thanked him.
구 총리 관저에 찾아가 감사 인사를 전했다.
You just visit and thank you?
그냥 방문하셔서 감사하셨나요?
Then... He didn't even want a reward from His Majesty,
그렇다면... 그는 폐하로부터 보상을 바라지도 않았습니다 .
what else can I do?
내가 또 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Since you already went to the Gu Residence, didn't you meet Gu Wanniang?
이미 구거주지에 가셨으니 구완냥을 만나지 않으셨나요?
(Broad and Open Minded)
(넓고 열린 마음)
Why did I see Gu Wanniang?
구완냥을 왜 봤지?
I don't care why you met him.
당신이 그 사람을 왜 만났는지 상관 없어요 .
Ying, are you jealous?
잉, 질투하는 거야?
No.
아니요.
You're jealous.
당신은 질투심이 많습니다.
Absolutely not.
절대적으로하지.
I want to go out of town to meet my father.
나는 아버지를 만나러 시내로 나가고 싶다 .
I'm coming so you can rest easy.
내가 왔으니 편히 쉬세요.
No need.
필요 없음.
Don't be jealous anymore.
더 이상 질투하지 마세요.
Ladies and Gentlemen, please have a look and take your pick.
신사 숙녀 여러분, 보시고 선택해 보시기 바랍니다.
Nuts in our shop
우리 가게의 견과류
dense, crunchy, and the delicious taste lasts a long time in the mouth.
촘촘하고 바삭바삭하며 입안에 오래도록 맛있는 맛이 지속됩니다.
You will definitely be satisfied.
당신은 확실히 만족할 것입니다.
I want a pack of everything here .
나는 여기에 있는 모든 것을 담은 팩을 원합니다.
Please wait a moment.
잠시만 기다려주세요.
(Wollong)
(월롱)
At that time you said in the letter that after entering the capital,
그때 당신은 편지에 수도에 들어간 후 이렇게 말했습니다.
we have to come together to this dried fruit shop.
우리는 이 말린 과일 가게에 함께 모여야 해요 .
Today, it finally came true.
오늘, 그것이 마침내 실현되었습니다.
I bought so much this time it's enough for you to eat for a while.
이번에 너무 많이 사서 한동안 드셔도 충분할 것 같아요.
Why do you sound a bit reluctant?
왜 조금 꺼려하는 것 같나요?
I don't mind.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
I just thought who knows when we will be able to meet again
그냥 우리가 언제 다시 만날 수 있을지 누가 ​​알까 싶었는데
after parting today.
오늘 이별 후.
Shiqi suddenly acted childish.
Shiqi는 갑자기 유치한 행동을 했습니다.
That was quite surprising.
그것은 매우 놀라운 일이었습니다.
Initially, I wanted to buy just a little.
처음에는 조금 사고 싶었어요 .
That way, you'll think of me whenever it's over.
그러면 끝날 때마다 내 생각을 하게 될 거야.
However, I then thought it would be a good idea to buy more.
하지만 나중에는 더 구입하는 것이 좋겠다는 생각이 들었습니다.
That way, you'll think of me when you eat it. It is better.
그러면 먹으면서 내 생각이 나겠지. 더 좋습니다.
Who will think of you when you eat dried fruit?
말린 과일을 먹으면 누가 당신을 생각할까요 ?
Me.
나.
I will remember you when I eat it.
먹으면 생각날 것 같아요 .
However,
하지만,
your favorite
당신이 가장 좋아하는
would also be my favorite.
또한 내가 가장 좋아하는 것입니다.
Sir, this is your dried fruit.
선생님, 이것은 당신의 말린 과일입니다.
Thank You.
감사합니다.
Ayo.
아요.
Madam looks much better and is also more stable when walking.
마담님이 훨씬 좋아보이고 걸을 때에도 더 안정적입니다.
Miss Taozi said, as long as it is well maintained,
타오자 선생님은 관리만 잘하면 된다고 하더군요.
Madam will be fine later.
부인은 나중에 괜찮을 거예요.
Commander He arrives!
지휘관 그가 도착했다!
Mrs.
부인.
Is Madam feeling better today?
부인 오늘은 좀 나아졌나요?
It's much better.
훨씬 나아졌습니다.
Come here and sit.
여기 와서 앉으세요.
Thank you Madam.
고마워요 부인.
Judging from the complexion of her face, Madam was much better.
얼굴의 안색으로 보아 부인이 훨씬 나아졌습니다.
Taozi told me that Madam's body would be very weak
도자는 마님 몸이 많이 약할 거라고 하더군요.
after the poison is gone
독이 사라진 후
and need to consume snow ginseng to improve health.
건강을 개선하려면 눈삼을 섭취해야 합니다 .
I told King Qin about this.
나는 진왕에게 이 사실을 말했다.
Then, King Qin chose some good snow ginseng
그러다가 진왕은 좋은 눈삼을 골랐다
and asked me to take it to the palace to give to Madame.
그리고 그것을 궁전으로 가져가서 부인께 드리라고 했습니다 .
Convey my thanks to King Qin.
진(秦)왕께 감사의 말씀을 전합니다 .
Madam, there is no need to hesitate.
부인, 망설일 필요가 없습니다.
Some time ago,
전자,
I heard Miss say that you are from the Cui Family Army.
미스 님이 최씨군 출신이라고 들었습니다 .
At the request of King Qin,
진왕(秦王)의 요청으로
You continue to stay in the palace to look after me.
당신은 나를 돌보기 위해 계속해서 궁전에 머물고 있습니다 .
I've really caused trouble for Miss.
제가 정말 선생님을 힘들게 했어요.
No.
아니요.
Madam is too shy.
부인은 너무 부끄러워요.
Talking about caring,
배려에 대해 이야기하고,
Aunt Jin and the court ladies did it.
진 아주머니와 궁녀들이 그랬어요.
I just came here and accompanied Madam to chat.
방금 여기에 와서 부인과 함께 이야기를 나눴습니다.
Miss is King Qin's heartthrob, right?
Miss는 진왕의 가슴 뛰는 사람이죠?
Despite never having met King Qin,
진왕을 한 번도 만난 적이 없음에도 불구하고,
I once sent a secret letter to him
한번은 그 사람에게 비밀 편지를 보낸 적이 있어요.
in my most difficult situation.
내가 가장 어려운 상황에서.
The character can be seen from various details.
캐릭터는 다양한 세부 사항에서 볼 수 있습니다.
I know he has no female relatives in his residence.
나는 그의 집에 여자 친척이 없다는 것을 알고 있습니다 .
You must be his idol
당신은 그의 우상임에 틀림없어요
so that he can calmly entrust me to you.
그러면 그가 나를 당신에게 차분히 맡길 수 있을 것입니다.
Madam is truly very perceptive.
부인은 정말 통찰력이 뛰어납니다.
I am a person
나는 사람이다
unfaithful and immoral.
불성실하고 부도덕합니다.
Only death
오직 죽음뿐이다
that could end my life.
그건 내 인생을 끝낼 수도 있어요.
King Qin once promised me that time
진왕이 나에게 그때를 약속한 적이 있다.
he will help me find the Emperor's First Grandson.
그는 내가 황제의 첫째 손자를 찾는 데 도움을 줄 것입니다.
I know King Qin
나는 진왕을 안다
is a person who keeps promises.
약속을 지키는 사람이다.
My status is as the Previous Crown Princess.
내 지위는 전 왕세자비이다.
Now in the palace, my situation is very awkward and I don't feel free.
지금 궁궐에서는 상황이 매우 어색하고 자유롭지 못합니다.
I want to leave the palace,
궁궐을 떠나고 싶다.
go to a remote place,
먼 곳으로 가거나,
and settle somewhere.
그리고 어딘가에 정착해.
Please Miss inform King Qin
진왕에게 알려주십시오.
to grant my wish.
내 소원을 들어주기 위해.
Don't worry, madam.
걱정하지 마세요, 부인.
King Qin will definitely agree to arrange it.
진왕은 반드시 그것을 마련하는 데 동의할 것입니다.
Are you really surnamed He?
당신의 성은 정말로 He입니까?
Beautiful and appropriate.
아름답고 적절합니다.
It turns out you are also talented in flower arranging.
알고 보니 당신은 꽃꽂이에도 재능이 있는 것 같군요.
King Qin came the other day.
얼마 전 진왕이 왔다.
At first I wanted to ask you to come out to meet him.
처음에는 만나러 나오자고 하고 싶었어요 .
However, after that I thought just forget it.
하지만 그 후에는 그냥 잊어버리자고 생각했어요.
Now is not the right time, there will still be many opportunities in the future.
지금은 적절한 시기가 아니며, 앞으로도 많은 기회가 있을 것입니다.
Correct.
옳은.
After returning to the capital,
수도로 돌아온 후,
His Majesty gave rewards to all three teams.
폐하께서는 세 팀 모두에게 상을 주셨습니다.
However, only King Qin was not rewarded with anything.
그러나 진왕만이 아무런 보상도 받지 못했다.
I think there must be bad people on His Majesty's side.
폐하의 편에는 나쁜 사람도 있는 게 틀림없다고 생각합니다 .
Most likely,
아마도,
He believed the slander he heard.
그는 자신이 들은 비방을 믿었습니다 .
Things like this happen often.
이런 일이 자주 발생합니다.
His merits were so great that the Emperor felt threatened,
그의 공덕이 너무 커서 황제가 위협을 느꼈고,
don't know what to reward.
무엇을 보상해야할지 모르겠습니다.
Possibly, this is also something that makes it difficult for His Majesty.
아마도 이것은 폐하를 곤란하게 만드는 일이기도 합니다.
Actually,
실제로,
the status of the King of Qin was already the highest among the kings.
진왕의 지위는 이미 왕들 중에서 가장 높았다.
However, King Qin was not rewarded at all despite his great contribution
그러나 진왕은 큰 공헌에도 불구하고 전혀 보상을 받지 못했다.
by reclaiming the two capitals and restoring the Yu Dynasty.
두 수도를 되찾고 우 왕조를 복원함으로써.
That's ridiculous.
말도 안 돼요.
Do you think Dad...
아빠 생각엔...?
He is in his prime
그는 전성기이다
and has no intention of appointing a Crown Prince at this time.
그리고 현재로서는 왕세자를 임명할 생각이 없습니다 .
Otherwise, the one appointed must be King Qin.
그렇지 않으면 임명된 사람은 진왕이어야 합니다.
However, King Xin is the eldest son
그러나 신왕은 장남이다.
and King Qi was His Majesty's favorite son since childhood.
제왕은 어려서부터 폐하가 가장 좋아하는 아들이었습니다.
Since ascending the throne, His Majesty has not appointed a queen.
폐하께서는 즉위하신 이후로 왕비를 임명하지 않으셨습니다.
The only son born to the empress was a legitimate son.
황후에게서 태어난 유일한 아들은 적자였습니다.
Tomorrow, I plan to submit written suggestions,
내일은 서면 제안서를 제출할 예정입니다.
request His Majesty
폐하께 요청하십시오
to bestow a posthumous title on King Qin's biological mother.
진왕의 친어머니에게 사후 칭호를 수여하기 위해 .
King Qin made such a great contribution, that's as it should be
진왕이 이렇게 큰 공헌을 했으니 당연히 그럴 만하다.
his biological mother was given the posthumous title of Empress.
그의 친어머니는 사후 황후라는 칭호를 받았습니다 .
Reportedly, King Qin's biological mother had a humble background.
전해지는 바에 따르면, 진왕의 생모는 배경이 미천했습니다.
That is not important.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
She gave birth to King Qin, such an extraordinary son.
그녀는 이렇게 비범한 아들인 진왕을 낳았습니다 .
As his biological mother,
그의 생물학적 어머니로서,
didn't she deserve to be given the posthumous title of Empress?
그녀는 사후에 황후라는 칭호를 받을 자격이 있지 않았습니까 ?
(Istana Chaoqian)
(이스타나 차오첸)
I've decided.
나는 결정했다.
Lady Dong, the biological mother of King Xin and King Qi,
신왕과 제왕 의 생모인 동부인은
given the posthumous title of Empress of Zhaocheng.
조성황후(趙成皇后)라는 시호를 받았다 .
Lady Liu, King Qin's biological mother,
진왕의 생모인 유씨(劉夫)
given the posthumous title of Consort Zhaoyi.
Consort Zhaoyi라는 사후 칭호가 주어졌습니다 .
- This...
- 이...
This is not correct.
이것은 정확하지 않습니다.
His Majesty, according to the servant this is not accurate.
폐하, 신하의 말에 따르면 이것은 정확하지 않습니다.
Servant agrees with Great General Pei.
하인은 페이 장군의 말에 동의합니다.
The posthumous title was given because it was a gift from His Majesty
폐하께서 하사하신 것이기 때문에 시호가 주어졌습니다.
and because of human ethical logic.
그리고 인간의 윤리적 논리 때문입니다.
After King Qin mobilized troops from the Laolan Border,
진왕이 라오 란 국경에서 군대를 동원한 후 ,
he crushed the rebellion and retook two capitals.
그는 반란을 진압 하고 두 개의 수도를 다시 차지했습니다.
With such a large contribution,
이렇게 큰 공헌으로,
if his biological mother had only been Concubine Zhaoyi,
만약 그의 친어머니가 후궁 조이(Zhaoyi)였다면,
fear that it will be difficult to show His Majesty's grace
폐하의 은총을 나타내기가 어려울까 두려워
that shines in all directions.
그것은 모든 방향에서 빛난다.
His Majesty, according to the servant,
폐하의 말에 따르면,
Mistress Liu gave birth to the King of Qin
유씨는 진나라 왕을 낳았다.
should have been given the posthumous title of Empress.
사후에 황후라는 칭호를 받았어야 했습니다 .
Servant agrees.
하인이 동의합니다.
- Servant agrees.
- 하인이 동의합니다.
All of you
여러분
said that King Qin made a great contribution to reclaiming the two capitals.
진왕이 두 수도를 되찾는 데 큰 공헌을 했다고 한다.
What about the eastern capital?
동부 수도는 어떻습니까?
Do not be angry, Your Majesty.
화내지 마십시오, 폐하.
All because of the useless Ananda.
모두 쓸모없는 아난다 때문이다 .
Shut up.
입 다물어.
Mrs. Liu had a humble background.
Liu 부인은 겸손한 배경을 가지고 있었습니다.
Is it just because she is King Qin's biological mother,
단지 그녀가 진왕의 생모 이기 때문일까 ,
should she be given the posthumous title of Empress?
그녀에게 황후라는 사후 칭호를 주어야 할까요 ?
His Majesty, regarding the slave's biological mother from a simple background
폐하, 단순한 배경에서 노예의 생모에 관해
so that His Majesty does not like,
폐하께서 좋아하지 않으시도록,
request that the title of servant king be removed
종왕이라는 칭호를 삭제해 달라고 요청하다
and send servants to Laolan Border to guard the border.
라오란 국경으로 하인을 보내 국경을 지키게 하세요.
- This...
- 이...
You...
너...
Do not be angry, Your Majesty.
화내지 마십시오, 폐하.
As a child, it is appropriate
어릴적엔 딱 맞는데
King Qin was grateful to his biological mother who had given birth to him.
진왕은 자신을 낳아준 친어머니에게 감사했다 .
Please forgive the King of Qin.
진왕을 용서해 주십시오.
Get lost, get out of here!
길을 잃다, 여기서 나가라!
I don't want to see you , this disobedient child again!
다시 는 보고 싶지 않아 , 이 불순종한 자식아!
Get out!
나가세요!
He doesn't respect his father.
그는 아버지를 존경하지 않습니다.
He has no respect for his father!
그는 아버지를 존경하지 않습니다!
(A Virtuous Person Takes Great Responsibility)
(덕이 있는 사람은 큰 책임을 진다)
His Majesty's verbal command.
폐하의 구두 명령.
Remembering that King Qin had spoken harshly,
진왕이 엄하게 말한 것을 기억하고
insulted his father, and made a fuss at the palace meeting,
그의 아버지를 모욕 하고 궁중 회의에서 소란을 피웠다.
a special order was issued to remove King Qin
진왕을 제거하라는 특별 명령이 내려졌다.
from his position as chief military officer.
최고 군사 장교로서의 지위에서 .
He was ordered to introspect at the Qin King's Residence.
그는 진왕의 거주지에서 성찰하라는 명령을 받았습니다 .
He must obey orders,
그는 명령에 복종해야 하며,
can't leave a single step from the house,
집에서 한 발짝도 나가지 못하고 ,
cannot participate in military affairs,
군사업무에 참여할 수 없으며 ,
and may not discuss government affairs unilaterally.
국정에 대해 일방적으로 논의할 수 없습니다 .
That's all.
그게 다야.
Servant, Li Ni, is grateful for His Majesty's gift.
하인 리니는 폐하의 선물에 감사하고 있습니다.
(Calm and Focused to Achieve Goals)
( 목표 달성을 위해 침착하고 집중함 )
When I was little, my nanny aunt said,
제가 어렸을 때, 유모 이모가 말했습니다.
If I have a wish, make a bamboo dragonfly.
소원이 있다면 대나무 잠자리를 만들어주세요.
When he falls to the ground, my wish will come true.
그가 땅에 떨어지면 내 소원이 이루어질 것이다.
At that time, I really wanted to meet my mother.
그 당시 저는 어머니를 꼭 만나고 싶었습니다.
Everyone else has a mother, only I don't have one.
다른 사람들은 다 엄마가 있는데 나만 없어요.
So, I folded a lot of bamboo dragonflies.
그래서 대나무 잠자리를 많이 접었어요.
I climbed up the wall and took them down one by one.
나는 벽을 타고 올라가서 그들을 하나씩 무너뜨렸다.
Until
까지
everything was removed then I knew
모든 것이 제거된 후 알았습니다
that my nanny aunt was just comforting me.
내 유모 이모가 나를 위로하고 있었을 뿐이라고요.
No matter how much
아무리
bamboo dragonfly that I made,
내가 만든 대나무 잠자리,
This wish cannot be realized.
이 소원은 실현될 수 없습니다.
♪When the ocean is no longer wide♪
♪바다가 더 이상 넓지 않을 때♪
♪Are you still going to wait♪
♪아직도 기다릴 건가요♪
Give it back.
돌려 줘.
Lowly child!
낮은 아이!
Bring it back!
다시 가져와!
Your mother is the lowest of servants.
네 어머니는 하인 중에 가장 천한 사람이다.
You made him die as soon as he was born.
당신은 그가 태어나자마자 그를 죽게 만들었습니다.
Bring it back!
다시 가져와!
♪Will you still remember♪
♪아직도 기억하고 계시나요♪
♪Still miss this hometown♪
♪아직도 고향이 그리워요♪
Enough already.
이미 충분합니다.
Say,
말하다,
Why did you steal your sister's things?
왜 누나의 물건을 훔쳤나요?
I didn't take the item.
나는 그 물건을 가져가지 않았다.
He was the one who took my bamboo dragonfly and called me names.
내 대나무잠자리를 빼앗아 욕을 해 준 사람이 바로 그 사람이었다 .
What did he call you?
그 사람이 당신한테 뭐라고 전화했어요?
Try to say.
말해보세요.
You can't say that, can you?
그렇게 말할 수는 없잖아요?
You actually dare to lie?
정말 감히 거짓말을 하는 겁니까?
I do not lie.
난 거짓말을하지 않아.
You're still arguing!
아직도 논쟁 중이군요!
I do not lie!
난 거짓말을하지 않아!
You are indeed lying!
당신은 정말로 거짓말을 하고 있습니다!
You're still arguing!
아직도 논쟁 중이군요!
I am not lying!
나는 거짓말을 하지 않습니다!
- You are lying! - I do not lie!
- 당신은 거짓말! - 난 거짓말을하지 않아!
Watch out you argue again!
또 말다툼을 벌이는 걸 조심하세요!
I am not lying!
나는 거짓말을 하지 않습니다!
You are indeed lying!
당신은 정말로 거짓말을 하고 있습니다!
- You are lying! - I do not lie!
- 당신은 거짓말! - 난 거짓말을하지 않아!
You are lying!
당신은 거짓말!
I do not lie!
난 거짓말을하지 않아!
♪Maybe you'll also think about it once in a while♪
♪당신도 한 번쯤은 생각해 볼지도 모르죠♪
(Calm and Focused to Achieve Goals)
( 목표 달성을 위해 침착하고 집중함 )
When I was little,
내가 어렸을 때,
(Liu Chengfeng's grave) you once saved my life.
(Liu Chengfeng의 무덤) 당신은 한때 내 생명을 구했습니다.
Then, you come home.
그럼 집에 오세요.
No matter what I do,
내가 무엇을 하던지,
you support me silently.
당신은 나를 조용히 지원합니다.
When I make a mistake,
내가 실수를 했을 때,
You are also the one who helped me bear it.
내가 버틸 수 있게 도와주신 분도 당신이에요.
By using my name,
내 이름을 사용하여,
I don't know how many dangers you have gone through.
얼마나 많은 위험을 겪었는지 모르겠습니다 .
Eventually,
결국,
You also died saving me.
당신도 나를 구하고 죽었어요.
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
(마캄 류청펑)
You have been my son for more than ten years.
당신은 10년 넘게 내 아들이었습니다 .
This,
이것,
I erected this monument for you
나는 당신을 위해 이 기념비를 세웠습니다.
so that your real name can be revealed to the world.
당신의 진짜 이름이 세상에 공개될 수 있도록 .
However, in my father's heart,
그러나 아버지의 마음에는
You are always like my real son.
당신은 항상 내 진짜 아들과 같습니다.
Feng'er,
펭어,
Ayah
유모
will definitely avenge you.
반드시 복수할 것입니다.
From now on,
지금부터,
you're just you,
너는 바로 너야,
is no longer Cui Lin.
더 이상 추이린이 아닙니다.
You are Liu Chengfeng.
당신은 Liu Chengfeng입니다.
However, you will forever be Dad's son.
하지만 너는 영원히 아빠의 아들일 것이다.
You will always be my brother too.
당신도 항상 내 형제가 될 것입니다.
(Makam Liu Chengfeng)
(마캄 류청펑)
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
(Kuil Qingyun)
(구일칭윤)
I never considered both of us as employer and servant
나는 우리 둘을 고용주와 하인으로 생각한 적이 없습니다
could leave the royal palace alive.
살아서 왕궁을 떠날 수 있었습니다 .
Look,
바라보다,
the residence that King Qin arranged for you is very quiet.
진왕이 당신을 위해 마련한 집은 매우 조용합니다.
After all, there must be great blessings after escaping a great disaster.
결국 큰 재난을 면한 뒤에는 큰 축복이 있을 것입니다.
You still have to fetch the Emperor's First Grandson back.
이제 황제의 첫째 손자를 다시 데려와야 합니다 .
You will be happy and live long.
당신은 행복 하고 오래 살 것입니다.
(Residence of the King of Qin) There are 18 bends in the Laolan River,
(진왕 거주지) 노란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있고,
the first bend is a shallow pine tree,
첫 번째 굴곡은 얕은 소나무이고,
fish in the shallows of the pine trees
소나무 얕은 곳의 물고기들
- fat-fat, - Eat meat, Shiqi.
- 지방, - 고기 먹어, Shiqi.
not as beautiful as the girl's eyes.
그 소녀의 눈만큼 아름답지는 않아요.
- Laolan. - Shiqi.
- 라오란 - 시치
Come on, get the wine.
자, 와인을 가져오세요.
Third Sister, Fourth Sister!
셋째 언니, 넷째 언니!
Can!
할 수 있다!
There are 18 bends in the Laolan River.
라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다.
Spend it.
그것을 보내십시오.
Cheers!
건배!
Let's spend it!
소비하자!
♪There are 18 bends in the Laolan River♪
♪라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다♪
♪The first bend is a shallow pine tree♪
♪첫번째 굴곡은 얕은 소나무♪
♪Ada 18...♪
♪에이다 18...♪
- Young General Pei.
- 젊은 페이 장군.
Give a portion of lamb to Young General Pei.
젊은 페이 장군에게 양고기 일부를 주세요 .
Good!
좋은!
Try this lamb steak.
이 양고기 스테이크를 맛보세요.
Come on, give some meat to Young General Pei.
자, 페이 장군에게 고기를 좀 주세요.
Try our lamb steak.
양고기 스테이크를 맛보세요.
- Come on, one more. - Eat this.
- 자, 하나 더. - 이거 먹어.
Mari.
마리.
Young General Pei,
젊은 페이 장군,
this meat is delicious.
이 고기는 맛있어요.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Come on, continue drinking.
자, 계속 마셔요.
Continue.
계속하다.
- Shiqi, - Good wine.
- Shiqi, - 좋은 와인.
Come on, one more.
자, 하나 더.
the situation is like this.
상황은 이렇습니다.
Maybe you drink wine?
어쩌면 와인을 마실 수도 있나요?
grilling meat, and singing here?
여기서 고기를 굽고 노래를 부르나요?
Drink a glass first.
먼저 잔을 마셔보세요.
Is it ripe yet?
아직 익었나요?
Drink a glass.
유리를 마셔 라.
Did you know that
당신은 알고 계십니까
troops sent by Sun Jing towards Baiyue...
Sun Jing이 Baiyue를 향해 보낸 군대 ...
Taste whether this lamb is delicious or not,
이 양고기 가 맛있는지 맛보고 ,
look at the results of the grill this time.
이번에 그릴 결과를 보세요.
Sit down.
앉아.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Mari.
마리.
There are King Xin's spies outside.
밖에는 신왕의 스파이들이 있습니다.
- Lower your voice when talking. - Fulfill it.
- 말할 때는 목소리를 낮추세요. - 이행하세요.
I've been waiting for you for the past few days.
나는 지난 며칠 동안 당신을 기다리고 있었습니다 .
Although at this time Sun Jing
지금은 Sun Jing이지만
poisoned and unconscious at Tong Border,
통 국경(Tong Border)에서 중독되어 의식을 잃었습니다 .
he will come to his senses sooner or later.
그는 조만간 정신을 차릴 것입니다.
The troops he sent towards Baiyue were already on their way back.
그가 백월을 향해 보낸 군대는 이미 돌아가고 있었다.
If those troops gathered with Sun Jing at the Tong Border,
만약 그 군대가 손경과 함께 통국경으로 집결했다면,
that would be troublesome.
그건 곤란할 것 같아요.
Shiqi,
시치,
so what do you mean?
그래서 무슨 뜻이야?
I've been pondering for the past few days.
나는 지난 며칠 동안 고민을 해왔다.
The best way is
가장 좋은 방법은
think of a way to get Grand General Pei to send you to Changzhou.
페이대장군이 당신을 창저우로 보내도록 할 방법을 생각해보세요 .
Here is Changzhou.
여기는 창저우입니다.
Here is the Han River.
여기는 한강이다.
From south to north,
남쪽에서 북쪽으로,
here
여기
is the best place to intercept and kill the Baiyue expeditionary army.
백월 원정군을 요격하여 죽이기에 가장 좋은 곳입니다 .
Stay cool,
침착,
My father and I will definitely sort this out.
아버지와 나는 이 문제를 반드시 해결해 나갈 것입니다.
There is one more thing that needs your help.
당신의 도움이 필요한 것이 하나 더 있습니다.
I will go to any lengths to deal with your problems.
나는 당신의 문제를 해결하기 위해 최선을 다할 것입니다 .
No need to run into danger.
위험에 빠질 필요가 없습니다.
You just have to help me with this.
당신은 나를 도와주기만 하면 됩니다.
Stay cool.
침착.
Is there a verbal message from King Qin?
진왕이 구두로 전한 메시지가 있습니까?
Then, thank you for delivering the letter.
그럼, 편지를 전해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Would Commander He not read it?
사령관님은 그것을 읽지 않으시겠습니까?
It turned out to be Young General Pei
페이 젊은 장군으로 밝혀졌습니다
who came in person to deliver King Qin's letter.
진왕의 편지를 직접 전달하러 온 사람 .
Please deliver this letter to Commander He.
이 편지를 허 사령관에게 전해 주세요 .
No, you also know that she is now Miss Cui.
아니요, 그녀가 이제 Miss Cui라는 것도 알고 있습니다.
He was outside Luoyang City, at the Cui Family Army headquarters.
그는 뤄양시 외곽의 추이 가문군 본부에 있었습니다 .
Shiqi,
시치,
You have important things to discuss with the Cui Family Army
추이 가문 군대와 중요한 논의할 사항이 있습니다.
Or have you found a way to retake the eastern capital?
아니면 동부 수도를 탈환할 방법을 찾았나요 ?
Not both.
둘 다 아닙니다.
This is a personal thing.
이것은 개인적인 일입니다.
Despite this enormous Qin King's Residence
이 거대한 진왕의 거주지에도 불구하고
was surrounded by the Yulin Team very tightly
Yulin 팀에 매우 촘촘하게 둘러싸여 있었습니다.
by order of His Majesty,
폐하의 명령에 따라,
I can't believe you couldn't find anyone to deliver the mail.
당신이 우편물을 배달할 사람을 찾을 수 없었다니 믿을 수가 없어요 .
What about Erduo?
에르두오는 어떻습니까?
You may not know that now the Yulin Army is commanded
지금 위린군이 지휘하고 있다는 사실을 모르실 수도 있습니다.
to give tasks to the people in the residence every day.
매일 거주지 사람들 에게 임무를 부여합니다 .
No matter how great Erduo is,
에르두오가 아무리 훌륭하더라도,
he wouldn't be able to go and come home in a day.
그는 하루 안에 집에 갔다가 돌아올 수 없을 것입니다 .
Shiqi, I told you the Cui Family now...
Shiqi, 지금 Cui Family에 대해 말했어요 ...
Who said earlier that he was willing to go through danger without hesitation?
앞서 누가 위험을 무릅쓰고라도 서슴없이 감행하겠다고 말했습니까?
You changed your mind so quickly?
그렇게 빨리 마음이 바뀌었나요?
Also this box. This is a newly purchased snack.
또한 이 상자. 새로 구입한 간식입니다.
You deliver it, this is his favorite food.
배달해 주면 그 사람이 제일 좋아하는 음식이거든요.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
(Tang Cake Shop)
(탕 케이크 가게)
Shiqi is now locked up at home,
Shiqi는 지금 집에 갇혀있습니다.
but he always remembers to write you a letter.
하지만 그는 항상 당신에게 편지를 쓰는 것을 기억합니다.
You really won't read that letter?
정말 그 편지를 읽지 않을 건가요 ?
Don't worry, Young General Pei.
걱정하지 마세요, 페이 장군님.
Even if all the bad people in this world perish,
이 세상의 나쁜 사람들이 모두 멸망하더라도
King Qin will definitely be fine.
진왕(秦王)은 분명 괜찮을 것입니다.
His Majesty saved your life many times despite the risks,
폐하께서는 위험에도 불구하고 여러 번 당신의 생명을 구해 주셨고,
but you don't care at all.
하지만 당신은 전혀 신경 쓰지 않습니다.
It seems,
것 같다,
you really have a heart of stone.
당신은 정말로 돌 같은 마음을 가지고 있습니다.
The King of Qin did a great job this time.
이번에는 진왕이 큰 일을 해냈습니다.
If he remains in government, what reward can His Majesty give?
만일 그가 계속 정부에 있다면 폐하께서 무슨 보상을 주실 수 있겠습니까?
If His Majesty does not reward him,
폐하께서 그에게 보상을 하지 않으신다면,
whether his two older brothers, King Qin and officials in the government
그의 두 형인 진왕(秦王) 과 정부 관료들
will be afraid?
두려울까?
The King of Qin left angrily and was locked up.
진왕은 화가 나서 떠나갔고 감옥 에 갇혔습니다.
On the surface, his military powers appeared to be revoked.
표면적으로는 그의 군사권이 박탈된 것처럼 보였다.
But actually,
하지만 실제로는
had he really lost the Western Border Army?
그는 정말로 서부 국경군을 잃었던 걸까 ?
Young General Pei is also the one who leads the army to war,
젊은 장군 페이(Pei)는 군대를 전쟁으로 이끄는 장수이기도 하고 ,
should know when to attack, when to camp and rest,
공격할 때와 진을 치고 쉴 때 를 알아야 하며 ,
the principle is the same.
원칙은 동일합니다.
It's late.
늦었 어.
Young General Pei was not free to remain in the Cui Family Army.
페이(Pei) 장군은 추이 가문 군(Cui Family Army)에 남을 자유가 없었습니다 .
I won't take you.
나는 당신을 데려가지 않을 것입니다.
Until found.
발견될 때까지.
It wasn't Erduo who delivered the letter.
편지를 전달한 사람은 에르두가 아니었습니다.
Some are very disappointed, right?
어떤 분들은 매우 실망하셨죠?
No.
아니요.
You must be hungry at this time of night, right?
이 밤 시간에는 배가 고프겠죠 ?
Eat freshly delivered snacks.
갓 배달된 간식을 먹어보세요.
You're the best. I'm a little hungry.
당신은 최고예요. 조금 배가 고파요.
Eat it.
그것을 먹을.
Commander, this snack is not too sweet and will make you feel bad,
지휘관님, 이 간식은 너무 달지 않아서 기분이 상할 것 같아요.
really very delicious.
정말 맛있어요.
You really won't read that letter?
정말 그 편지를 읽지 않을 건가요 ?
How about you read it?
읽어보시면 어떨까요?
(Tang Cake Shop)
(탕 케이크 가게)
Why is there only blank paper?
왜 빈 종이만 있는 걸까요?
Commander, you expected that, didn't you?
지휘관님, 예상하셨죠?
What does this mean?
이것은 무엇을 의미 하는가?
Li Ni asks Pei Yuan to deliver the letter.
Li Ni는 Pei Yu에게 편지를 전달해달라고 부탁합니다.
That means even though he is locked up,
즉, 갇혀 있음에도 불구하고
there were still people he could use.
그가 사용할 수 있는 사람들이 아직 남아 있었습니다.
Apart from that, the Western Border Army also continued to listen to his orders.
그 외에도 서부국경군 역시 그의 명령을 계속해서 따랐다.
Anything else doesn't matter.
다른 것은 중요하지 않습니다.
Why waste ink?
왜 잉크를 낭비합니까?
You two smart people always go back and forth like this,
똑똑한 두 분은 항상 이렇게 왔다 갔다 하세요.
aren't you tired?
피곤하지 않아?
Correct.
옳은.
Unlike certain people who just need to blow the whistle,
호루라기를 불기만 하면 되는 어떤 사람들과는 달리 ,
then Erduo will immediately rush over.
그러면 Erduo가 즉시 달려올 것입니다.
♪If you forget the fire of love you once had♪
♪ 한때 느꼈던 사랑의 불길을 잊어버리신다면 ♪
♪Memories will be destroyed and drowned♪
♪기억은 파괴되어 익사합니다♪
♪Your heart is full of color♪
♪당신의 마음은 다채로워요♪
♪Makes it hard for me to forget our relationship♪
♪우리 관계를 잊기 힘들어요 ♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪그리움이 결코 버리지 않는다면♪
♪Hoping to return to the first time we met♪
♪ 처음 만났던 그때로 돌아가고 싶어 ♪
♪The destined warmth I want to leave you♪
♪ 당신에게 남기고 싶은 운명의 온기 ♪
♪If love can remember we once promised♪
♪사랑이 기억할 수 있다면 우리는 한때 약속했었죠♪
♪Even though this love hurts me, I will still live for you♪
♪이 사랑이 나에게 상처를 주더라도 나는 여전히 당신을 위해 살아갈 것입니다 ♪
♪Pulling out the limits of memory, waiting is the hardness of my heart♪
♪기억의 한계를 끌어내는 것, 기다림이 내 마음의 단단함♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪사랑이 우리의 약속을 기억할 수 있다면♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪역카르마여, 당신을 사랑한 것을 후회하지 마세요♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪당신에게 내 마음을 전하고 당신의 대답을 기다릴 의향이 있습니다 ♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪사랑이 우리의 약속을 기억할 수 있다면♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪역카르마여, 당신을 사랑한 것을 후회하지 마세요♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪당신에게 내 마음을 전하고 당신의 대답을 기다릴 의향이 있습니다 ♪